Sales calls, they work.
But a lot of things work.
If I came in here
and I had a really good chest,
and all I did was press-ups, I
would probably be under the illusion
that press-ups are really good for chest
development because it's what I've been
doing.
But there's just a few issues I have with
sales calls.
The first thing, the empty diary effect.
If I'm going on your VSL,
watching your content,
getting into your personal brand,
doing your seven hours,
and I get through to the sales call
and your diary's
fucking empty, I'm like, "Oh,
this can't be shit." You know
when you're on holiday,
you're in Italy,
you're walking down the cobbled street,
there's a nice restaurant.
You go in, there's no one sitting there.
"Babe, get the fuck back.
That place has salmonella." How do I know?
The locals know.
This place is empty,
we're going nowhere near it.
The more free that diary is,
you're getting a bounce rate,
but you're not getting
feedback on the bounce rate. People
are just leaving.
You're, "Oh,
why am I not getting any calls booked?"
Because your diary's fucking
empty. Then we've got the time wasters.
People that get on a call,
and they're like, "Oh,
I need to talk to my wife about
it." An hour of your time.
You think it's an hour of your time.
It's more than an hour because your call
was at 2:00, you finished your last client
at 12:00,
and now you can't really start another
task until the call.
So really, you've lost three hours.
Because before, you're like, "Oh,
I could start making some content.
Oh, but I've got a call at 2:00,
and I don't want to be tired
when I get on the
call.
I need to be my best so I can close the
sale." Or me, you put anything in my
diary, if you put it in at 3:00 PM,
the whole day is wasted because I'm just
thinking about the 3:00 PM thing.
I've got alarms on my phone going off,
so I don't
forget it. So some people with time,
they go, "Oh,
my close rate's 60%." I'm like,
"Whoa, hold on.
So 40% of people don't buy.
Oh." So out of 10 hours on calls,
four hours, people don't buy.
[gags] If you were to instead make content
or write email marketing emails,
you'd get better at that over time.
If you spend four hours a week writing
emails, you get good at writing emails.
You spend four hours a week making
content, you get better at making content.
You spend four hours a week getting told
that they need to talk to their partner.
No, no, no.